Welcome to SQL and Relational Database 101!
Database software usage is pervasive.
Its presence is everywhere, from retrieving money through an automatic teller machine,
to badge access at a secure office location.
Yet it is basically taken for granted every day by billions of users worldwide.
In computer science, databases are among the most researched domains.
And, there are multiple types of databases to suit various industry requirements.
In this course, you'll learn the relational database model and the basics of the SQL language
through a series of components: There are five modules, covering an introduction to
relational databases (including definitions), information and data models, and relational
model constraints.
You are also introduced to five basic SQL statements, including some advanced techniques
in retrieving data from one or more relational database tables.
At the end of each module, there are three review questions to test your knowledge and
understanding of the concepts.
You'll also be able to apply what you've learned through four hands-on labs so you can try
out these concepts yourself.
Then, you'll be ready to take the 15-question final exam!
From start to finish, this course should take you less than four hours.
And, as Spock said in the movie Wrath of Kahn, "For everything there is a first time".
So let's get started!